ABRAHAM CHRISTOPHER

Frontend Developer (React Js)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abrahamchristopher https://github.com/cabraham1 Abuja, Nigeria christopherabraham8@gmail.com

Professional Summary

In my Professional years of Experience as a Frontend Engineer, I have worked on Software Products, getting involved from the design phase to the deployment phase in agile cross-functional teams. My long-term goal is to build, maintain and understand market needs for software products that would transform businesses.

Technical Skills

Programming languages/Frameworks/Technologies: JavaScript ES6, HTML, CSS, React js, Styled Component, CSS libraries, React test tools, Responsive Web applications, Data Structures, Algorithms, Object-Oriented Programming.

Tools: Git, Bitbucket, Trello, Open Project, VS Code, Figma, Webpack, Babel, Git Actions, Docker, Postman, Swagger docs, Chrome Dev Tools, React Dev Tools.

Work Experience

Frontend Developer, Interface Connect Limited, Abuja, NG (January 2022 – Present)

Interface connect Limited provides software products as a service, and provides mentorship, in the ICL Software Academy.

- Technologies: SCSS, JavaScript, Postman, Trello, React, Typescript, Nextjs
- Deploying front-end applications to production, displaying and manipulating data from APIs on the client-side,
 end-to-end testing, building UI functional components, and handling code reviews.
- Working with clients to develop the overall user interface of a web applications
- Incorporating applications, graphics, audio and video components into client web application
- Creating tools to enhance the user experience web applications
- Ensuring web applications are responsive and accessible across various platforms
- Routine testing web applications for better user experience and quality assurance.
- Designed and developed the company's website, creating a user-friendly interface that is fully responsive and optimized for search engine indexing and useability.
- Debugging

Junior Frontend Developer Intern, Tiidalab, Abuja, NG (June 2021 – December 2021)

With vast experience and an excellent track record, Tiidelab has positioned itself as an ideal solution for all software development projects.

- The Boxmonie web application (Fintech) is a thrifting system that allows users create cohort, contribute money together and each take turns to receive the lump sum been contribute.
- Technologies: JavaScript, React Js, React Query, Redux, Context, Git
- Introduced and implemented a design system with React that improved consistency in development and aided new developers onboarding by a larger percentage across various teams.
- Built and deployed frontend and backend fintech web application, handled state management and UI logic using React hooks, and documented components as a style guide using React.
- Translate designs and wireframes into high-quality code, built functional reusable components using React js and styled component, and worked with REST APIs from Swagger docs to integrate with the frontend.
- Documented task flow and process improvements in Confluence, and updated task progress using Trello.
- Learned the agile workflow from design to deployment as well as presenting features at demo sessions.
- Peer learning, coding partner session with rigorous code reviews
- Collaborating with teams remotely using Vscode Live share, Git and GitHub.

Frontend Developer Intern, Federal Ministry of Humanitarian Affairs, Disaster Management and Social Development, Abuja, NG (**September 2019 – December 2019**)

FMHDS manages, train and equips youth to become tech savvy with the support from the federal government of Nigeria, in a social scheme call N-power.

- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Figma, WordPress
- Built and maintained business websites for clients with WordPress.
- Implemented UI prototypes/designs for multiple in-office web-based applications using Figma
- Developed a working knowledge of frontend technologies through self-guided tutorials, with an emphasis on object-oriented programming.
- Designed and developed E-commerce website, this system solved the problem physical market place where users place order on items from the online store and will be delivery to them.
- Learned Content management system, WordPress, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, asynchronous programming, and the concept of web technology

Education

HND (2022) in Electrical Electronics Engineering - Federal Polytechnic, Idah Kogi State.

Languages

English - Native Language